{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. In ballistic galvanometer, the frame on which the coil is wound is non-metallic. It is ____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To avoid the production of induced e.m.f.",
        "b": "To avoid the production of eddy currents.",
        "c": "To increase the production of eddy currents.",
        "d": "To increase the production of induced e.m.f."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. A null type of instrument as compared to a deflection type instrument has ______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A higher accuracy",
        "b": "A lower sensitivity",
        "c": "A faster response",
        "d": "All the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. In a second order system, the peak overshoot is 100 &percnt;. The value of damping factor is :",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1",
        "b": "0.707",
        "c": "0",
        "d": "0.5"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. The sensitivity of a moving coil galvanometer can be increased by decreasing ____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The number of turns in the coil.",
        "b": "The area of the coil.",
        "c": "The magnetic field.",
        "d": "The couple per unit twist of the suspension."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The deflection &theta; is related to the electric current I in a galvanometer by the relation",
      "answers": {
        "a": "I &prop; &theta;",
        "b": "I &prop; tan &theta;",
		"c": "I &prop; sin &theta;",
        "d": "I &prop; cos &theta;"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. What is the shape of the magnet, used in D’Arsonval galvanometer when a large flux is required in the air gap ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Convex cylindrical magnet",
        "b": "Horse-shoe magnet",
        "c": "Concave cylindrical magnet ",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Phosphor- bronze wire is used in suspension because it has _____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A large couple per unit twist",
        "b": "A small couple per unit twist",
        "c": "Low conductivity",
        "d": "High Sensitivity"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. A moving coil instrument has the following data.<br/> Number of turns = 100, width of the coil = 20 mm, depth of the coil = 30 mm, flux density in the gap = 0.1 Wb/m<sup>2</sup>. Calculate the deflecting torque when carrying a current of 10 mA.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "6 &times; 10<sup>-5</sup> Nm",
        "b": "4 &times; 10<sup>-5</sup> Nm",
        "c": "10 Nm",
        "d": "None of the above"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }, 
    
	
	{
      "question": "9. A moving coil instrument has the following data.<br/> No. of turns = 100, width of the coil = 20 mm, depth of the coil = 30 mm, flux density in the gap = 0.1 Wb/m<sup>2</sup>, the deflection torque = 30 &times; 10<sup>–6</sup> Nm. Calculate the current through the moving coil.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2 mA",
        "b": "5 mA",
        "c": "10 mA",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. In measurement systems, which of the following static characteristics are desirable ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Accuracy",
        "b": "Sensitivity",
		"c": "Reproducibility",
        "d": "All the above"
       
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
	
  ]
}